[

Sensory Integration Education
=============================](https://www.sensoryintegrationeducation.com/)

Toggle menu Menu

Sensory Integration Education Privacy Policy
============================================

BACKGROUND:

Sensory Integration Education understands that your privacy is important to you and that you care about how your personal data is used. We respect and value the privacy of everyone who visits this website, www.sensoryintegratoneducation.com (“Our Site”) and will only collect and use personal data in ways that are described here, and in a way that is consistent with our obligations and your rights under the law.

Please read this Privacy Policy carefully and ensure that you understand it. Your acceptance of this Privacy Policy is requested at first use of the site or sign-up.

### 1\. Definitions and Interpretation

In this Policy, the following terms shall have the following meanings:  

|     |     |
| --- | --- |
| “Account” | means an account required to access and/or use certain areas and features of Our Site; |
| “Cookie” | means a small text file placed on your computer or device by Our Site when you visit certain parts of Our Site and/or when you use certain features of Our  Site. Details of the Cookies used by Our Site are set out in Part 14, below; and |
| “Cookie Law” | means the relevant parts of the Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) Regulations 2003; |

### 2\. Information About Us

Our Site is operated by Sensory Integration Education, a trading name of SI Network (UK & Ireland) Ltd registered in England under company 0506830.

Registered address: SI Network (UK & Ireland) Ltd, International House, 61 Mosley Street, Manchester, M2 3HZ[](https://www.google.com/maps/place/Sensory+Integration+Education/@51.483452,-1.0841937,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x487699ad3e25dbfb:0xa5596aa20e55d1eb!8m2!3d51.483452!4d-1.082005), UK.

Address: SI Network (UK & Ireland) Ltd, International House, 61 Mosley Street, Manchester, M2 3HZ[](https://www.google.com/maps/place/Sensory+Integration+Education/@51.483452,-1.0841937,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x487699ad3e25dbfb:0xa5596aa20e55d1eb!8m2!3d51.483452!4d-1.082005), UK.

Our company is not VAT registered.

Data Protection Officer: Fiona Insch

Email address: [\[email protected\]](https://www.sensoryintegrationeducation.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

Phone: +44 (0)118 207 2773

Postal address: SI Network (UK & Ireland) Ltd, International House, 61 Mosley Street, Manchester, M2 3HZ[](https://www.google.com/maps/place/Sensory+Integration+Education/@51.483452,-1.0841937,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x487699ad3e25dbfb:0xa5596aa20e55d1eb!8m2!3d51.483452!4d-1.082005), UK.

### 3\. What Does This Policy Cover?

This Privacy Policy applies only to your use of Our Site. Our Site may contain links to other websites. Please note that we have no control over how your data is collected, stored, or used by other websites, and we advise you to check the privacy policies of any such websites before providing any data to them.

### 4\. What Is Personal Data?

Personal data is defined by the UK GDPR and the Data Protection Act 2018 (collectively, “the Data Protection Legislation”) as ‘any information relating to an identifiable person who can be directly or indirectly identified in particular by reference to an identifier’.

Personal data is, in simpler terms, any information about you that enables you to be identified. Personal data covers obvious information such as your name and contact details, but it also covers less obvious information such as identification numbers, electronic location data, and other online identifiers.

### 5\. What Are My Rights?

Under the Data Protection Legislation, you have the following rights, which we will always work to uphold:

a) The right to be informed about our collection and use of your personal data. This Privacy Policy should tell you everything you need to know, but you can always contact us to find out more or to ask any questions using the details in Part 15.

b) The right to access the personal data we hold about you. Part 13 will tell you how to do this.

c) The right to have your personal data rectified if any of your personal data held by us is inaccurate or incomplete. Please contact us using the details in Part 15 to find out more.

d) The right to be forgotten, i.e. the right to ask us to delete or otherwise dispose of any of your personal data that we hold. Please contact us using the details in Part 15 to find out more.

e) The right to restrict (i.e. prevent) the processing of your personal data.

f) The right to object to us using your personal data for a particular purpose or purposes.

g) The right to withdraw consent. This means that if we are relying on your consent as the legal basis for using your personal data, you are free to withdraw that consent at any time.

h) The right to data portability. This means that if you have provided personal data to us directly, we are using it with your consent or for the performance of a contract, and that data is processed using automated means; you can ask us for a copy of that personal data to re-use with another service or business in many cases.

i) Rights relating to automated decision-making and profiling. We do not use your personal data in this way.

For more information about our use of your personal data or exercising your rights as outlined above, please contact us using the details provided in Part 15.

It is important that your personal data is kept accurate and up-to-date. If any of the personal data we hold about you changes, please keep us informed as long as we have that data.

Further information about your rights can also be obtained from the Information Commissioner’s Office or your local Citizens Advice Bureau.

If you have any cause for complaint about our use of your personal data, you have the right to lodge a complaint with the Information Commissioner’s Office. We would welcome the opportunity to resolve your concerns ourselves, however, so please contact us first, using the details in Part 15.

### 6\. What Data Do You Collect and How?

Depending upon your use of Our Site, we may collect and hold some or all of the personal and non-personal data set out in the table below, using the methods also set out in the table. Please also see Part 14 for more information about our use of Cookies and similar technologies. We do not collect any ‘special category’ or ‘sensitive’ personal data or personal data relating to children.

|     |     |
| --- | --- |
| Data Collected | How We Collect the Data |
| Identity Information e.g.name | Thinkific learning platform, ConvertKit marketing platform, Social Media eg Facebook |
| Contact information including email address, address | Thinkific learning platform, ConvertKit marketing platform, Social Media eg Facebook |
| Payment information, including card details | Stipe Payment system |
| Profile information, including preferences, interests, login details, purchase history | Thinkific learning platform |
| Technical information, including IP address, browser type | Thinkific learning platform, Google Analytics |
| Academic information for those applying for the MSc in SI Postgraduate courses | Airtable form |

###   

### 7\. How Do You Use My Personal Data?

Under the Data Protection Legislation, we must always have a lawful basis for using personal data. The following table describes how we may use your personal data and our lawful bases for doing so:

|     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- |
| What We Do | What Data We Use | Our Lawful Basis |
| Registering you on Our Site. | Name and email address | To provide you access our products and services. |
| Providing and managing your Account. | Name and email address | To provide you access our products and services. |
| Providing and managing your access to Our Site. | Name and email address | To provide you access our products and services. |
| Personalising and tailoring your experience on Our Site. | Name and email address | To provide you access our products and services. |
| Communicating with you. | Name and email address | To communicate existing and new services and news on sensory integration. |
| Passing on academic information to Sheffield Hallam University for those students applying for MSc in SI Postgraduate courses | Academic information | To allow the university to enrol you as a student. |

With your permission and/or where permitted by law, we may also use your personal data for marketing purposes, which may include contacting you by email, telephone or text message with information, news, and offers on our products and services. You will not be sent any unlawful marketing or spam. We will always work to fully protect your rights and comply with our obligations under the Data Protection Legislation and the Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) Regulations 2003, and you will always have the opportunity to opt out. We will always obtain your express opt-in consent before sharing your personal data with third parties for marketing purposes, and you will be able to opt out at any time.

Third Parties (including Thinkific, the platform provider whose content appears on Our Site may use third-party Cookies, as detailed below in Part 14. Please refer to Part 14 for more information on controlling cookies. Please note that we do not control the activities of such third parties, nor the data that they collect and use themselves, and we advise you to check the privacy policies of any such third parties.

We will only use your personal data for the purpose(s) for which it was originally collected unless we reasonably believe that another purpose is compatible with that or those original purpose(s) and need to use your personal data for that purpose. If we do use your personal data in this way and you wish us to explain how the new purpose is compatible with the original, please contact us using the details in Part 15.

If we need to use your personal data for a purpose that is unrelated to, or incompatible with, the purpose(s) for which it was originally collected, we will inform you and explain the legal basis which allows us to do so.

In some circumstances, where permitted or required by law, we may process your personal data without your knowledge or consent. This will only be done within the bounds of the Data Protection Legislation and your legal rights.

### 8\. How Long Will You Keep My Personal Data?

We will not keep your personal data for any longer than is necessary in light of the reason(s) for which it was first collected. Your personal data will, therefore be kept for the following periods (or, where there is no fixed period, the following factors will be used to determine how long it is kept):

|     |     |
| --- | --- |
| Type of Data | How Long We Keep It |
| Name | As long as the account is in use or for a length of time we are required to keep financial transaction records. |
| Email address | As long as the account is in use or for a length of time we are required to keep financial transaction records. |
| Payment information, including card details | As long as the account is in use or for a length of time we are required to keep financial transaction records. |
| Profile information including preferences, interests, username and password, purchase history. | As long as the account is in use. |
| Technical information including IP address and browser type. | As long as the account is in use or for a length of time we are required to keep financial transaction records. |
| Academic information to Sheffield Hallam University for those students applying for MSc in SI Postgraduate courses. | As long as the student is studying the MSc in SI Postgraduate courses. |

###   

### 9\. How and Where Do You Store or Transfer My Personal Data?

We may store some or all of your personal data in countries outside of the UK. These are known as “third countries”. We will take additional steps in order to ensure that your personal data is treated just as safely and securely as it would be within the UK and under the Data Protection Legislation as follows:

We will only store or transfer personal data in or to countries that are deemed to provide an adequate level of protection for personal data. For further information about adequacy decisions and adequacy regulations, please refer to the Information Commissioner’s Office.

Please contact us using the details below in Part 15 for further information about the particular data protection safeguards used by us when transferring your personal data to a third country.

The security of your personal data is essential to us, and to protect your data, we take a number of important measures, including the following:

* limiting access to your personal data to those employees, agents, contractors, and other third parties with a legitimate need to know and ensuring that they are subject to duties of confidentiality;
* procedures for dealing with data breaches (the accidental or unlawful destruction, loss, alteration, unauthorised disclosure of, or access to, your personal data), including notifying you and/or the Information Commissioner’s Office where we are legally required to do so.

###   

### 10\. Do You Share My Personal Data?

We will not share any of your personal data with any third parties for any purposes, subject to the following exceptions.

If we sell, transfer, or merge parts of our business or assets, your personal data may be transferred to a third party. Any new owner of our business may continue to use your personal data in the same way(s) that we have used it, as specified in this Privacy Policy.

In some limited circumstances, we may be legally required to share certain personal data, which might include yours, if we are involved in legal proceedings or complying with legal obligations, a court order, or the instructions of a government authority.

We may sometimes contract with the following third parties to supply certain products and services.

|     |     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- | --- |
| Recipient | Activity Carried Out | Sector | Location |
| Thinkific | Website and Learning Management System Provider | Learning Management | Canada  <br>https://www.thinkific.com/security-overview/ |
| Thinkific’s Third party add-on software providers, e.g. Zoom, Appointo etc. | Video Meetings and appointment booking | Video Meetings, Scheduling Software | Canada  <br>https://www.thinkific.com/security-overview/ |
| Sheffield Hallam University | Academic data for students passed to the university. | University | UK  |

If any of your personal data is shared with a third party, as described above, we will take steps to ensure that your personal data is handled safely, securely, and in accordance with your rights, our obligations, and the third party’s obligations under the law, as described above in Part 9.

If any personal data is transferred outside of the UK, we will take suitable steps in order to ensure that your personal data is treated just as safely and securely as it would be within the UK and under the Data Protection Legislation, as explained above in Part 9.

If we sell, transfer, or merge parts of our business or assets, your personal data may be transferred to a third party. Any new owner of our business may continue to use your personal data in the same way(s) that we have used it, as specified in this Privacy Policy.

In some limited circumstances, we may be legally required to share certain personal data, which might include yours, if we are involved in legal proceedings or complying with legal obligations, a court order, or the instructions of a government authority.

### 11\. How Can I Control My Personal Data?

In addition to your rights under the Data Protection Legislation, set out in Part 5, when you submit personal data via Our Site, you may be given options to restrict our use of your personal data. In particular, we aim to give you strong controls on our use of your data for direct marketing purposes (including the ability to opt-out of receiving emails from us, which you may do by unsubscribing using the links provided in our emails and at the point of providing your details and by managing your Account).

You may also wish to sign up for one or more of the preference services operating in the UK: The Telephone Preference Service (“the TPS”), the Corporate Telephone Preference Service (“the CTPS”), and the Mailing Preference Service (“the MPS”). These may help to prevent you from receiving unsolicited marketing. Please note, however, that these services will not prevent you from receiving marketing communications that you have consented to receiving.

### 12\. Can I Withhold Information?

You may access certain areas of Our Site without providing any personal data at all. However, to use all features and functions available on Our Site, you may be required to submit or allow for the collection of certain data.

You may restrict our use of Cookies. For more information, see Part 14.

### 13\. How Can I Access My Personal Data?

If you want to know what personal data we have about you, you can ask us for details of that personal data and for a copy of it (where any such personal data is held). This is known as a “subject access request”.

All subject access requests should be made in writing and sent to the email or postal addresses shown in Part 15.

There is not normally any charge for a subject access request. If your request is ‘manifestly unfounded or excessive’ (for example, if you make repetitive requests), a fee may be charged to cover our administrative costs in responding.

We will respond to your subject access request within 14 days and, in any case, not more than one month after receiving it. Normally, we aim to provide a complete response, including a copy of your personal data, within that time. In some cases, however, particularly if your request is more complex, more time may be required up to a maximum of three months from the date we receive your request. You will be kept fully informed of our progress.

### 14\. How Do You Use Cookies?

Our Site may place and access certain first-party Cookies on your computer or device. We use Cookies to facilitate and improve your experience of Our Site and to provide and improve our products and services. We have carefully chosen these Cookies and have taken steps to ensure that your privacy and personal data is protected and respected at all times.

Our Site may place and access certain first-party Cookies on your computer or device. First-party Cookies are those placed directly by us through our software platform, Thinkific, and are used only by us. We use Cookies to facilitate and improve your experience of Our Site and to provide and improve our products and services. By using Our Site you may also receive certain third-party Cookies on your computer or device. Third-party Cookies are those placed by websites, services, and/or parties other than us. Third-party Cookies are used on Our Site to recognise your device and provide you with a personalised experience to attribute visits to our websites to third-party sources and to serve targeted ads from Google, Facebook, Instagram and other third-party vendors. In addition, Our Site uses analytics services provided by Google Analytics, which also uses Cookies. Website analytics refers to a set of tools used to collect and analyse usage statistics, enabling us to better understand how people use Our Site.

### 15\. How Do I Contact You?

To contact us about anything to do with your personal data and data protection, including making a subject access request, please use the following details (for the attention of SIE Support)

Email address: [\[email protected\]](https://www.sensoryintegrationeducation.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

Telephone number: +44 (0)118 207 2773

Postal Address: SI Network (UK & Ireland) Ltd, International House, 61 Mosley Street, Manchester, M2 3HZ[](https://www.google.com/maps/place/Sensory+Integration+Education/@51.483452,-1.0841937,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x487699ad3e25dbfb:0xa5596aa20e55d1eb!8m2!3d51.483452!4d-1.082005), UK

### 16\. Changes to this Privacy Policy

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. This may be necessary, for example, if the law changes or if we change our business in a way that affects personal data protection.

Any changes will be immediately posted on Our Site, and you will be deemed to have accepted the terms of the Privacy Policy on your first use of Our Site following the alterations. We recommend that you check this page regularly to keep up-to-date. This Privacy Policy was last updated on 5 October 2023.

**Embedded Community Box Privacy Policy for Find a Local SI Therapist Directory**

In the following Policy,

\* "we" refers to Fraction 7, Ltd, makers of Community Box

1\. What data we store on your device

  We do not store any data on your device.

2\. What we track

 We monitor activity in, and uploads to, Boxes. This is both to ensure there are no violations of the Terms and Conditions, or in order to comply with requests from law enforcement or other authorised government agencies.

3\. What data we store

We store any data that is necessary for the display and processing of a Box (e.g., the box contents themselves, and any settings or customisations that have been made to the Boxes). We also store your contact details so that we can get in touch with you for purposes in connection with the business. We also store usage metrics in order for our internal teams to improve the Community Box experience.

4\. What data we share

We are committed to your privacy and we do not share data with any 3rd parties, except in the case of requests from law enforcement and other authorised government agencies.

5\. How we process your data

Your data is stored and processed in the form of reports, and real-time monitoring and metrics. These are used internally within our company to allow us to improve our services so we can improve the Community Box user experience.

6\. How you can obtain and erase the data we store about you

If you wish to obtain copies of any data we store about you, or for us to erase that data (note that this would imply terminating your account with us), then you can email [\[email protected\]](https://www.sensoryintegrationeducation.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) with the subject line "GDPR request" and we will follow up with you to ascertain what action is required.

Copyright Sensory Integration Education 2024

[\[email protected\]](https://www.sensoryintegrationeducation.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)  
Sensory Integration Education is a trading name of SI Network (UK and Ireland) Ltd.  
International House, 61 Mosley Street, Manchester, M2 3HZ. UK. Co No 05068304. UKPRN: 10096399
